# EESHA DHANKER

eeshadhanker@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/eesha-dhanker-929a301b4/

I am a third year Computer Engineering major at the University of Toronto, specializing in software. I am passionate about learning new concepts and am particularly interested in applying my knowledge to create computer programs to solve real world problems. I have experience with a variety of programming languages such as C, C++, Java and Python, and am good at problem solving.

# **EDUCATION**

SEPTEMBER 2019 - APRIL 2023 (Expected)

**BASC, COMPUTER ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO** 

#### **RELEVANT COURSES**

- Applied Fundamentals of Machine Learning
- Algorithms and Data Structures
- Operating Systems
- Object Oriented Programming
- Software Communications and Design
- Hardware Communications and Design

# WORK EXPERIENCE

**MAY 2023 - AUGUST 2023** 

#### **SOFTWARE ANALYST INTERN, CITI BANK**

- Conducted SQL queries to analyze and modify database tables
- Created a hierarchical mapping system of jobs and their dependencies
- Used python and pandas library to extract, clean and analyze credit card transaction data to determine potential patterns of credit card fraud

**MAY 2022 - APRIL 2023** 

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN, BAYER**

- Full-stack development in the Radiology department for dose management application
- Implemented features in web application to send and receive medical examinations, record patient data and generate alerts when required
- Created forms for users to input patient information, and saved info to SQL databases

MAY 2020 - JULY 2020

#### **SOFTWARE INTERN, MASHGIN**

Created computer vision programs using OpenCV and Python

- Developed programs that extract image attributes such as facial encodings from files in order to recognize faces from live and still images
- Created a database using python for reading and writing files that store image attributes such as facial encodings, names, etc.
- Researched OpenCV library for relevant functions to be used in developing computer vision algorithms

#### **OCTOBER 2016 – JUNE 2019**

### **TEACHING ASSISTANT, SPIRIT OF MATH**

- Worked with teachers to teach students of various grades advanced math concepts
- Hosted a drop in session to provide extra help for students

# **PROJECTS**

# **AI Skin Cancer Classifier**

- Developed and trained a model using transfer learning to identify and classify different kinds of skin cancer
- Researched and retrieved relevant datasets to use for training
- Utilized AlexNet transfer learning model and Artificial Neural Network layers

#### **GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEM**

- Developed a mapping application similar to Google Maps
- Written in C++ with 2 API layers for map functionality
- Interactive UI written with EZGL and GTK graphics
- Implemented several path finding algorithms such as the Greedy algorithm

#### **Multi-Threaded Webserver**

- Implemented a buffer system for multiple threads, allowing multiple requests to be handled at once
- Utilized OS concepts such as locking, buffers, synchronization, etc. to approach the producer-consumer problem

# **PONG**

- Recreated the classic game of Pong using OpenCV GUI/Numpy matrices
- Included user interface with a scoreboard to keep track of player scores
- See the code for this project on my GitHub: https://github.com/eesha-d/Pong

#### **REVERSI**

- Recreated a 2 player version of the game Reversi
- Involved setting up the board configuration and checking move legality for each move before proceeding to carry out the actions of the game

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Solo piano performance at Carnegie Hall, New York Crescendo International Competitions
- Debate club co-president at Unionville High School
- Co-founder and co-president of the University Prep club at Unionville High School
- Dean's Merit Award, University of Toronto
- 2020 Youth Impact challenge award proposed solution for recycled/refurbished computers for low-income families